vidyarthiplus.com 2015-03-26

# Privacy Policies - Vidyarthiplus (V+) - Indian Students Online Education Forum

**Last modified:** August 14 , 2014 

Vidyarthiplus (V+) policies are described briefly and well explained in this page. We encourage you to read our Privacy Policy carefully while using our service and doing business with us.

You can use Vidyarthiplus (V+) service in many different ways such as - to search and download study materials , Communicate with other Students or Teachers , to share your Study Materials or Information. When you share study materials or information with us by creating a Vidyarthiplus Account, we can make those services even better – to make sharing study materials with others quicker and easier.  
Vidyarthiplus respect your privacy and the information collected from the V+ Members are not shared with any third party or with another.   
In this page you can find what are the information we collect and why we collect it. How we use that information.

**Information we collect :**  
Inorder to Share Study Materials and to communicate with other Members, you have to sign up for a publicly visible Vidyarthiplus Account, which may include your name , date of birth and photo. When you do, we will ask for personal information, like your name, data of birth , email address, telephone number , and education qualification details. You may also sign up or sign in for a publicly visible Vidyarthiplus Account by using social network such as Facebook , Google Plus and Twitter.   
By signing up or signing in for a publicly visible Vidyarthiplus Account using Social Networks , we collect the following Information :  
Full Name  
Profile Picture,  
Date of Birth,  
Location,  
Biography,  
Gender,.

**Information we collect for SLE**  
Share Learn Earn (SLE) is a service for Vidyarthiplus Members which allows to Share the Study Materials , Learn from the Study Materials and Earn from the Study Materials.  
Inorder to process the Payout for the SLE, we collect the following Information when you are using SLE Service.  
For Mobile Recharge :  
Mobile Number,  
Mobile Operator,  
Recharge Amount.

For Bank Transfer:  
Account Number  
Account Name  
IFSC Code

The information collected to SLE Payout will not be shown or shared to any Members , or any third parties.

**Managing and Controlling your personal information :**  
By Default Your Name, Date of Birth and Photo are shown in your Profile Page, You can manage the information Visibility on the Settings Page.  
Email ID and Mobile Numbers will not been shown to other members or any third party.  
If you don't like to receive Email or Private Message from other members and Vidyarthiplus Team, Change the Email Preference in "Edit Option" on the Settings Page.  
For Profile Settings : [Click Here](https://www.vidyarthiplus.com/vp/usercp.php)  
If you have any problem in removing or modifying the personal information, Feel Free to contact us : admin@vidyarthiplus.com

**Reason for Collecting the Information :**  
* For Internal Vidyarthiplus Member Details Record.  
* We use the Information to understand your Needs and Improve our Service.  
* Based on the Settings on your Profile Page , we may periodically send important emails about the Notification from Various University / Colleges or other information which we think you may find interesting. If you don't like receive Email's Vidyarthiplus, you can Unsubscribe anytime from your Profile Settings or by clicking on Unsubscribe link which will be present at the bottom of the Email.  
If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

**Security :** We promise that your information is secure. We have installed SSL Certificate (also known as a Secure Certificate) installed on our server to provide security for our website by encrypting communications between the server and the person visiting the website. We also follow the latest electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences. We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about webpage traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system. Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us. You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

**Links to other websites :**  
Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

**Contact Us** If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below:  
Write to Us : [Click Here](https://www.vidyarthiplus.com/vp/misc.php?page=contact)  
or   
Mail to : admin@vidyarthiplus.com

Phone : +91-9840-847-673 , +91-8015-215-224 

Note : Our Privacy Policy are subject to change with or without notice. So you should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes.
